我想除了这一年紧张的事实之外，还有新的期望
I imagine that with renewed expectation beyond the fact that the year has been intense
imagino que con expectativa renovada más allá de que el año ha sido intenso
你如何想象这次重返比赛、恢复领先的平局？
How do you imagine this return to the competition, to resume a tie in which you have the leaders?
¿Cómo imaginás esta vuelta a la competencia, a retomar una eliminatoria que los tienen líderes?
你所宣称的一切意味着不放松并继续以同样的方式竞争。
with everything that what you proclaim means of not relaxing and continuing to compete in the same way.
con todo lo que significa esto que ustedes pregonan de no relajarse y seguir compitiendo de la misma manera.
它使我们处于一个位置......
It finds us in a position...
Nos encuentra en una posición...
但这个九月的日子总是有其特殊性。
But this September date always has particularity.
Pero siempre esta fecha de septiembre tiene particularidad.
他们把球队换成了机会很少的球员。
They have changed teams to players who have few opportunities.
Han cambiado de equipo a jugadores que vienen de pocas ocasiones.
也许我用你的相机拍了一些照片。
Maybe I've done a little filming with your camera.
a lo mejor he hecho poco rodaje con su cámara
奎溪。
Quixi.
这是一个特殊的日子，因为有很多球员，不仅是阿根廷人，而且来自所有球队。
It is a particular date because many players, not only Argentinians, but from all teams.
Es una fecha particular porque muchos jugadores, no solo los argentinos, pero de todas las selecciones.
我们将努力继续保持水平
We will try to continue maintaining the level
intentaremos seguir manteniendo el nivel
愿球队继续坚守我们的阵线。
May the team continue in the line we are on.
que el equipo siga en la línea en la que estamos.
并努力以最好的方式完成日期板。
and trying to finish the date board in the best way.
y de intentar terminar el tablero de fecha de la mejor manera.
有趣，我们想继续。
interesting and we want to continue.
interesante y queremos continuar.
我不会问你设备，但我会问你流程是什么
I'm not going to ask you the equipment, but I am going to ask you what the process is to
No te voy a preguntar el equipo, pero si te voy a preguntar cuál es el proceso para
今天是安赫尔栽培的第11次缺席，也是梅西的第10次缺席
The 11th of the absence of Ángel's cultivation and the 10th of the absence of Messi today
El 11 de la ausencia del cultivo de Ángel y el 10 de la ausencia hoy de Messi
抓住线并将其插入
grab the line and plug this in
agarrar la línea y enchufar esto
重要的是，佩戴丝带的球员是让球队感到心碎的球员。
It is important that the player wearing the ribbon is a player that the team feels broken about.
Es importante que el jugador que lleve la cinta sea un jugador en el cual el equipo se sienta roto.
提出。
presented.
presentado.
你看，没有你的价值。
Look, without your value.
Fíjese, sin tu valor.
我们能够做一些事情，但仍然有一些球员身体状况不够好。
We were able to do something but there were still some players who were not fit enough.
pudimos hacer algo pero faltaban algunos jugadores todavía que no estaban en condiciones.
嘿嘿
hey, hey
oye, oye
至于衬衫，好吧，当它不乱的时候，我想安赫尔·科雷亚有时会用它......
And about the shirt, well, when it hasn't been messy I think Ángel Correa has sometimes used it...
Y lo de la camiseta, bueno, cuando no ha estado lío creo que a veces lo ha usado Ángel Correa...
当他不在我们身边的时候，他也在参加另一场比赛……不，不是这样，不是这样。
The time he wasn't with us, he was also in another game... No, that's not it, that's not it.
La vez que no estaba con nosotros, en otro partido también estaba... No, esa no es, esa no es.
我们知道10号有主人，5号没有主人。
We know that number 10 has an owner, number 5 does not have an owner.
Sabemos que la 10 tiene dueño, la 5 no tiene dueño
而不是
and not
y no
就这样吧，这是一件会给你很多爱的衬衫。
So be it, it is a shirt that will give you a lot of love.
Así sea, es una camiseta que le va a dar mucho cariño.
Leo，早上好，我们正在视频中。
Leo, good morning, we are on video.
Leo, buen día, estamos en video.
你好，有消息吗？
Hello, all the news?
Hola, ¿todo de noticias?
怎么样了？
How's it going?
¿Cómo te va?
我想问你关于玛丽亚的悼念，明天对他和阿根廷公众来说意味着什么......
I wanted to ask you about María's tribute, what tomorrow will surely mean for him and for the Argentine public to be able to...
Quería preguntarte por el homenaje de María, lo que va a significar mañana seguramente para él y para el público argentino poder...
告别这座不朽的建筑，我有勇气向您介绍一下。
Farewell to the monumental and I have the audacity to introduce you to you.
Despedido de la monumental y me tengo el atrevimiento de presentarte a vos.
我们处在一个环境...
We are in an environment...
Estamos en un ambiente...
如果我没有成为一名足球运动员，我会想成为一名赛车手。
If I hadn't been a soccer player, I would have liked to be a racing driver.
Si no hubiera sido jugador de fútbol, hubiera gustado ser piloto de automobilismo.
那么你能告诉我你对周日弗朗哥·科拉平托首秀的感受吗？
So you can tell me your feelings about what happened on Sunday with Franco Colapinto's debut?
¿Para que me digas tus sensaciones de lo que pasó el domingo con el debut de Franco Colapinto?
我有一个天才，我要做或住在马略卡岛或......
I have a genius that I'm going to do or live in Mallorca or...
Tengo un genio que me voy a hacer o vivir en Mallorca o...
我从来没有见过他，他也骑自行车
and I never got to see him and he rides a bike too
y nunca lo pude ver y anda en bici también
比赛同时还有比赛
there were games at the same time of the race
había partidos a la vez de la carrera
我们划分了屏幕，所有的屏幕，一边是一级方程式赛车，一边是一场比赛，我认为是利物浦对阵曼彻斯特的比赛，或者……
and we divided the screens, all the screens, Formula 1 on one side and a match that I think was Liverpool-Manchester or...
y dividimos las pantallas, las pantallas todas, la Fórmula 1 por un lado y un partido que creo que era el Liverpool-Manchester o...
我不记得它到底是什么了，事实是它产生亚麻，它让我为所有阿根廷人感到兴奋。
I don't remember exactly what it was and the truth is that it generates flax, it excites me for all Argentinians.
No recuerdo bien cuál era y la verdad es que genera lino, me ilusiona para todos los argentinos.
拥有一名飞行员并按照他的方式完成任务。
to have a pilot and to have done it the way he did it.
tener un piloto y que lo haya hecho de la manera que lo hizo.
每个人都产生了幻觉……
and everyone is hallucinating with the...
y todos están alucinando con la...
你好你好。
Hello hello.
Hola, hola.
历史上最好的之一，留下了令人难忘的遗产。
one of the best in history and leaves an unforgettable legacy.
de los mejores de la historia y deja un legado imporrable.
每个人都必须以某种方式坚持对他们所做的事情
everyone has to somehow hold on to what has been done to them
todos tienen que de alguna manera agarrarse en lo que le ha hecho
但我从来没有提到过。
But I never mention it.
Pero no lo refiero nunca.
那么，足球使冠军变得更加灵活，它增加了负担。
and football, then, has made the titles more agile, it has raised the burden.
y el fútbol, entonces ha dejado más ágil a los títulos, ha elevado el porrable.
除此之外，他是一个了不起的男孩，因为这让他更加巨大
and besides that he is a spectacular boy because that makes him even more gigantic
y además de eso es un chico espectacular porque eso hace que todavía sea gigante más todo
也许你在团队中没有那种优势，但他是一个不可思议的人。
when maybe you don't have that ascendancy in a group, but he is an incredible guy.
cuando a lo mejor no tenés esa ascendencia en un grupo, pero él es un chico increíble.
无论它的价值如何，所以让我们希望人们
whatever it's worth, so let's hope people
todo lo que valga, así que esperemos que la gente
因为一个人在
because a guy in the
porque nos ha dejado un llegado también espectacular un tipo en el
非常专业。
very professional.
muy profesionales.
这里。
Here.
Aquí.
在美好的一天，Centro Activo Paradispo Radio 的 Narela，我想问你......
And on a good day, Narela, Centro Activo Paradispo Radio, I would like to ask you...
Y en el buen día, Narela, Centro Activo Paradispo Radio, me gustaría pedirte...
对巴勃罗·迪巴拉的新电话进行反思，并借此机会问问自己是否……
a reflection about this new call to Pablo Dybala and take the opportunity to ask yourself if...
una reflexión acerca de esta nueva convocatoria a Pablo Dybala y aprovechar para preguntarte si...
您赞赏罗马决定留在意大利参加比赛。
You appreciated Rome's decision to stay and compete in Italy.
le valoraste la decisión de quedarse a competir en Italia a Roma.
没有关系...
has no relation...
no tiene relación...
他了解自己是什么，如何生活，并留在他深爱的俱乐部，抛开其他事情。
He understands what he is, how he lives and has stayed at the club he loves so much, leaving aside other things.
Entiende lo que es él, cómo vive y se ha quedado en el club que tanto quiere y dejando de lado otras cosas.
但电话是足球
but the call was football
pero la convocatoria ha sido futbolística
早上好，莱昂内利。
Good morning, Leonelli.
Buen día, Leonelli.
广播电台的古斯塔沃·查罗什。
Gustavo Charroche for Radio.
Gustavo Charroche para Radio.
如果您有任何不适，以及其他方面（如果您有疑问）
discomfort you have and the other if you have questions
molestia que tiene y la otra si es que tenés interrogantes
事实是，这种事总是发生在我们身上。
The truth is that it always happens to us.
La verdad es que siempre nos pasa.
或者做第一部分的训练，他已经能做到了。
or do a first part of the training, he has been able to do it.
o hacer una primera parte del entrenamiento, él lo ha podido hacer.
根据他的情况，这并不会改变我们的比赛方式，因为最终......
Based on how he is, it doesn't change the way we play much because in the end...
En base a como esté él, no es que nos cambia mucho la manera de jugar porque al final...
我们将继续玩同样的游戏。
We will continue playing the same.
Seguiremos jugando igual.
我不知道球队的其他人怎么样，或多或少已经决定了。
I don't know how the rest of the team is, it's more or less decided.
No sé cómo está el resto del equipo, más o menos está decidido.
因为水质不好。
Because the water is bad.
Porque está mal la agua.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
您谈到了在非常关键的时刻球迷与佩里·玛丽亚的关系发生了180度的转变。
You talked about the 180º change in the fans' relationship with Peri María at a very critical moment.
El cambio de 180º en la relación de los hinchas con el Peri María, lo contaste en un momento muy crítico.
你得花多少钱...
How much did you have to...
¿Cuánto tuviste que...
不是为了你，我要为你付出多少？
Not for you, how much did I have to put in for you?
Por vos no, ¿cuánto te hice que poner vos?
尤其是安赫尔为阿根廷队提供了实现所有目标所需的连续性。
especially in relation to Ángel to provide this continuity that he needed in the Argentine team to achieve all the objectives.
en especial en relación a Ángel para dar esta continuidad que necesitaba en la selección argentina para lograr todos los objetivos.
我想问你的另一件事是阿根廷国家队在历史上又处于什么位置。
And the other thing I wanted to ask you is where in history the Argentine National Team was again.
y la otra lo que quería preguntarte es en qué lugar de la historia la Selección Argentina volvió a estar.
想要来这里的时候，有一段时间他没有和我一起来，而且时间很短。
of wanting to be here, there was a moment when he didn't come with me and it was a very short time.
de querer estar acá, hubo un momento que conmigo no venía y fue un tiempo muy corto
传播，他们是非常年幼的男孩
transmitted and they were very young boys
transmitía y eran chicos muy jóvenes
球员们迈出了一步，他继续和我们一起观看，又是一名球员。
The players took the step, he continued watching with us and was one more.
Los jugadores dieron el paso, él siguió viendo con nosotros y fue uno más.
稍后见。
and see you later.
y hasta luego.
场上30分钟，他没有打过，他打过90分钟，他打过60分钟，他一直带着自己的东西。
30 minutes on the field, he has not played, he has played 90, he has played 60 and he has always carried his own thing.
30 minutos dentro de la cancha, no ha jugado, ha jugado 90, ha jugado 60 y siempre ha portado lo suyo.
对于我们来说
For us that
Para nosotros eso
永远不要有一张坏脸
to never have a bad face
de no tener nunca una mala cara
因为我们没有从他那里得到任何优点，无论如何，或者在任何情况下，从他知道如何理解它的同伴那里得到任何优点。
because we have no merit whatsoever from him and in any case or in any case from his companions who have known how to understand it.
porque no tenemos ningún mérito todo de él y en cualquier caso o en todo caso de sus compañeros que lo han sabido entender.
在台阶上我无法告诉你，但是......
and on the step I couldn't tell you, but...
y en el escalón no sabría decirte, pero...
他拥有阿根廷历史上最好的头衔，我不能不尊重很多球员。
He has had the titles of the best in the history of Argentina and I cannot disrespect a lot of players.
en los títulos de los mejores de la historia de Argentina la ha tenido y no puedo faltar el respeto a un montón de jugadores.
在他的整个历史中，他都打出了巨大的表现。
He has had enormous play throughout his history.
Ha tenido enorme jugar en toda su historia.
会有人认为以前的也很好，也会有人认为现在的也很好
and there will be people who will think that those from before were also very good and there will be people who will think that those from now are very good
y habrá gente que pensará que los de antes también eran muy buenos y habrá gente que pensará que los de ahora son muy buenos
伟大的球员，这给我们带来了巨大的快乐。
of the great players and that has given us enormous joy.
de los grandes jugadores y que nos ha dado una alegría enorme.
另一次是与大托卢戈。
The other time with Big Tolugo.
La otra vez con Big Tolugo.
我想问你一些新面孔的事。
I want to ask you about some new faces.
Te quiero preguntar por algunas caras nuevas.
昨天我们与朱利亚诺·西蒙尼和瓦伦丁·卡斯特拉诺进行了交谈。
Yesterday we were talking with Juliano Simeone and Valentín Castellano.
Ayer estuvimos hablando con Juliano Simeone y con Valentín Castellano.
也许我们可以添加 X 费尔南德斯。
Maybe we can add X Fernández.
Podemos sumar quizá a X Fernández.
不要认为他们会继续一点一点地服用，或者突然他们可能有几分钟的时间，这是一个过程，正如你所看到的，而且时间很短
without thinking that they continue to take it little by little or suddenly they may have minutes, it is a process as you see it and a short time
sin pensar que siguen llevándolo de a poco o de pronto pueden tener minutos, es un proceso como lo ves y una cortita breve
关于 AFA 发起的一项关于非歧视的运动。
about a campaign launched by AFA about non-discrimination.
sobre una campaña que lanzó AFA acerca de la no discriminación.
我们都受到了伤害。
We are all harmed.
nos perjudicamos todos.
而不是安全地治疗它。
than to treat it safely.
que tratarlo con seguridad.
让人们了解并鼓励他们的团队，不要歧视。
Let people be aware and encourage their team without discriminating.
que la gente sea consciente y que vaya a alentar a su equipo sin discriminar.
除此之外，由于这个原因，明天我们比赛的人数会减少
beyond the fact that we will play tomorrow with fewer people for that reason
más allá de que nosotros juguemos mañana con menos gente por eso
在我们生活的时代，这已经没有任何意义了。
It doesn't make sense anymore in the times we live in.
No tiene sentido más en la época que vivimos.
与选择，但我们相信他们可以做出贡献
with the selection but we believe that they can contribute
con la selección sino que creemos que pueden aportar
根据游戏的内容以及我们对游戏的看法，他们毫无疑问可以玩，因为他们通过表现来展示它
based on what the game will be and what we see of the game, they can play without a doubt because they are showing it by being
base a lo que será el partido y a lo que veamos del partido pueden jugar sin duda porque lo están demostrando por estar
来自西班牙接力赛的马可·杜兰。
Marco Durán from Spain Relay.
Marco Durán de Relevo de España.
四年前的二月，我们在马德里进行了一次采访。
Four years ago we did an interview in Madrid in February.
Hace cuatro años hicimos una entrevista en Madrid en febrero.
那是2020年，在2019年美洲杯之后，你告诉我，你告诉我两三次阿根廷需要获胜。
It was 2020, after the 2019 Copa América, you told me, you told me two or three times that Argentina needs to win.
Era 2020, después de la Copa América 2019, vos me decías, me dijiste dos o tres veces que Argentina necesita ganar.
他需要获胜，在赢得了他们赢得的一切之后，这一点一直困扰着我
he needs to win and that stuck with me after having won everything they won
necesita ganar y a mi me quedo grabado eso después de haber ganado todo lo que ganaron
您认为阿根廷现在需要什么才能继续增长？
What do you think Argentina needs now to continue growing?
¿Vos qué crees que necesita ahora Argentina para seguir creciendo?
我必须回顾一下
I have to review
tengo que repasar
竞争永远比胜利更重要，永远是
It is always competing more than winning, always being
es siempre el competir más que ganar, siempre estar
竞争，团队及其同伴看到对方
competing, that the team and its companions see the other that
compitiendo, que el equipo y sus compañeros vean al otro que
竞争，让对手看到...
competing, let the rival see...
compitiendo, que el rival vea...
在一个人移动的环境中，在这种情况下就是健康。
that in the environment where one moves, in this case it is health.
que en el ambiente donde uno se mueve, en este caso es la salud.
大家都看到了一个方向，这个方向就是继续最大限度的竞争。
Everyone sees that there is a direction and the direction is to continue competing to the maximum.
todos vean que hay una dirección y la dirección es seguir compitiendo al máximo.
因为从未迷失过，以及你昨天注意到的那一刻......
for never lost and what you noticed yesterday in a moment...
por perdido nunca y lo que le fíjese ayer en un momento...
我和他们交谈并告诉他们我们现在在做什么。
I spoke to them and told them what we were doing now.
Les hablé y les dije qué hacíamos ahora.
去年我想，当你上班并取得一些成就时
last year I think, when you arrive at work and achieve something
el año pasado creo, cuando uno llega en su trabajo y logra algo
好东西
something good
algo bueno
更重要的是因为他们不仅在国家队踢球
and more so because they not only play in the national team
y más ellos porque ellos no solo juegan en la selección
我一直这么说，他们的基因里就有竞争的基因，永远处于最佳状态。
And I have always said it, that they have it in their DNA to compete, to always be at their best.
Y lo he dicho siempre, que lo llevan en su ADN de competir, de estar siempre al máximo.
如果有人不理解，就让他们改变，我认为这就是问题所在。
If there is someone who doesn't understand it, let them change, I think that is the problem.
Si hay alguno que no lo entiendo, que cambie, yo creo que es el problema.
输了但是……
lose but...
perder pero...
表现出继续想要竞争的意愿，我认为这是最重要的。
The demonstration of continuing to want to compete, which I think is the most important thing of all.
La demostración de seguir queriendo competir, que creo que es lo más importante de todo.
怎么样了？
How's it going?
¿Cómo te va?
《门多萨邮报》的卢卡斯·布尔戈亚强化了这个问题……
Lucas Burgoa from the Mendoza Post newspaper, reinforcement of the question that...
Lucas Burgoa del diario Mendoza Post, refuerzo a la pregunta que...
后续进展如何？
How has the follow-up process been?
¿Cómo ha sido el proceso de seguimiento?
情人节，当轮到他上场时，你认为他能为球队做出什么贡献？
Valentine's day and what do you think he can contribute to the team when it's his turn to add a minute?
de valentín y que crees que le pueda aportar al equipo cuando le toque sumar minuto
最终他没有来，我们相信现在是一个很好的机会
In the end he has not come, we believe that now is a good opportunity
al final no ha venido, creemos que ahora es una buena oportunidad
而在没有狮子座的情况下...
and in the absence of Leo...
y ante la ausencia de Leo...
他的水平很高，我们不认识他，但我们希望他能见到......
He is at a good level and we do not know him and we want him to meet...
está en buen nivel y que no conocemos y queremos que él reúne...
条件有效、动作良好、交往良好
conditions that are valid, have very good movements, associate well
las condiciones que son válidas, tienen muy buenos movimientos, se asocia bien
打好球，就是这样……
Playing ball well, that's what...
Jugar bien a la pelota que es lo que...
教练，莱昂内怎么样？
Coach, how is Leone?
Entrenador, ¿cómo está Leone?
哈维尔·阿帕里西奥，我们为萨尔塔、为白羊座而活。
Javier Aparicio, we are live for Salta, for Aries.
Javier Aparicio, estamos en vivo para Salta, para Aries.
10队，我想问你两件事。
Team 10, I wanted to ask you two things.
Equipo 10, te quería preguntar dos cosas.
你和迪巴拉就他的未来进行过真正的交谈吗？
Did you have any real talks with Dybala about his future?
¿Tuviste alguna charla verdadera con Dybala acerca de su futuro?
如果你提出建议，他们就会讨论这个问题。
If you advised it, they talked about it and well, a question.
si lo consejaste hablaron de eso y bueno la una pregunta
考虑到缺席情况以及如果您考虑一下接下来会发生什么，它已经被还押
It is already remanded taking into account the absences and what is coming if you think about a
ya está remanida teniendo en cuenta las ausencias y lo que se viene si volvés a pensar en un
一起或单独判断或判断的可能性，你如何处理这个问题。
the possibility of judging or judging together or separately, how you handle this.
la posibilidad de lautar o juzgar juntos o separados, cómo va manejando esto.
谢谢。
Gracias.
巴勃罗和他的移情的主题并不......
the theme of Pablo and his transference does not...
el tema de Pablo y su transferencia no...
我没有参与，只有当我们打电话给他时，他被传唤，我们问他是否会留下来
I didn't get involved, only when we called him, he was summoned, we asked him if he would stay
no me metí, solo cuando lo llamamos, estaba convocado, le preguntamos si se quedaba
个人的，在很多情况下是足球决定，在其他情况下也是人生决定
personal, in many cases football decisions, in other cases also life decisions
personales, en muchos casos decisiones futbolísticas, en otros casos decisiones también de vida
我们不会介入，因为我们都经历过这种情况。
and we are not going to get involved because we have all been in that situation.
y no nos vamos a meter porque hemos estado todos en esa situación.
至于劳塔罗和朱利安……
And in relation to Lautaro and Julián...
Y con relación a Lautaro y Julián...
我总是会回答同样的问题，如果你们一起玩过就可以一起玩
and I will always answer the same thing, if you have played together you can play together
y voy a responder siempre lo mismo, si han jugado juntos pueden jugar juntos
我们相信这将取决于我们将要面对的对手，或者也取决于每个人目前的情况。
and we believe that it will depend on the rival we are going to face or also the circumstances of each one at the moment.
y creemos que dependerá del rival que vamos a afrontar o también las circunstancias de cada uno en el momento.
阿尔库迪亚锦标赛。
of the Alcudia tournament.
del torneo de la Alcudia.
我知道现在外面很难
I know it's difficult out there now,
Yo sé que por ahí es difícil ahora,
思考可能更广泛，但
Thinking about it may be more extensive but
pensarlo quizás es más extenso pero
您走过的旅程以及您对阿根廷足球与他的联系有何看法？
the journey traveled and what do you also think of that association of Argentine football with him.
el trayecto recorrido y qué pensás también de aquella asociación del fútbol argentino con él.
起初我不知道那一年我在做什么，但是……
At first I didn't know what I was doing that year, but...
Primero no sabía que hacía ese año, pero...
但是，嘿，本质本身并没有改变我的存在方式。
But hey, the essence itself has not changed my way of being at all.
Pero bueno, la esencia misma no ha cambiado absolutamente nada mi manera de ser.
理解足球，这是我与人相处的方式，而不仅仅是球员。
understanding football, my way of relating to people, not just the players.
entender el fútbol, mi manera de relacionarme con la gente, no solo con los jugadores.
尽管这是一场快速的比赛
although it was a fast tournament
aunque haya sido un torneo veloz
对我来说巨大的记忆是很多事情的开始
huge memory for me it was the beginning of a lot of things
enorme recuerdo para mí fue el inicio de un montón de cosas
一样的，管理永远是一样的，我们周围的人永远是一样的
the same, the management is always the same, the people around us are always the same
igual, la directiva siempre la misma, la gente que está alrededor nuestro siempre la misma
一切都随着宪法而被放大......
and everything has been magnified with the constitution of the...
y se ha todo magnificado con la constitución de los...
最新的东西，但它们的本质和支持都是一样的
of the latest things but the essence with them remains the same and the support as well
de las cosas últimas pero la esencia con ellos sigue siendo la misma y el apoyo también
它改变了我们很多。
and it has changed us a lot.
y nos ha cambiado mucho.
你和迪玛利亚谈到了明天将在球场上与他一起致敬，你会喜欢吗？
You spoke with Di María about the tribute that will be given tomorrow being with him on the field, would you have liked that?
Hablaste con Di María acerca de que el homenaje que se va a hacer mañana sea con él en cancha, ¿tú hubieses gustado eso?
去玩吗？
to go playing?
que se vaya jugando?
就这样吧。
take it that way.
tomarlo de esa manera.
所以后来想想，我很巧合地在飞机上遇见了他，因为我们一起飞去……
So thinking about it later, I coincidentally met him on the plane because we flew together to...
Entonces pensándolo bien después, casualmente lo encontré en el avión porque volamos juntos para...
我们相信重要的是人们看到他说再见但在球场上
that we believed that the important thing was that people see him say goodbye but that on the field
que creíamos que lo importante era que la gente lo vea despedirse pero que adentro de la cancha
比赛很重要，对手也必须得到尊重，我认为
match is very important, the rival must also be respected and I think that
partido es muy importante el rival también hay que respetarlo y creo que
但与他交谈时他告诉我，看，他很清楚他的......
But talking to him he told me, look, he was clear that his...
pero hablándolo con él me dijo, mirá, él la tenía clara que su...
选拔已结束决赛
the selection had finished the final
la selección había terminado la final
如果你之前必须这样做，那将不会有任何结果。
If you have to do it before, nothing will come of it.
Si uno lo tiene que hacer antes, no le sale nada.
莱昂内，这里是英雄克拉林的奶奶安西洛塔，你好吗？
Leone, here, the grandma ancillota for the hero clarín, how are you?
Leone, acá, la abuela ancillota para el héroe clarín, ¿cómo estás?
问问自己关于里奥，关于梅西，是的，在这一切中
Ask yourself about Leo, about Messi, yes in all this
Preguntarte por Leo, por Messi, si en todo esto
这段时间，他受了很多伤，可以看到他的脚踝，还在恢复中。
During this time, the injury that he suffered a lot, he can see his ankle and he is still recovering.
en este tiempo de la lesión que sufrió bastante, se ve en el tobillo y todavía lo tiene recuperándose.
你说，如果你有了解，他显然会跟进，但知道他是怎样的，你从远处看他是怎样的。
You said, if you have understanding, he obviously follows up, but knowing how he is, how you see him from a distance.
Hablaste, si tenés comprensión obviamente le hace un seguimiento, pero saber cómo está, cómo lo ven ustedes desde la distancia.
如果您已经知道下个月就可以得到它。
If you already know that you will be able to have it next month.
si ya sabés que lo vas a poder tener el próximo mes.
也可以看看你对佩切拉和阿库尼亚回归的反思。
and also see your reflection on the returns of Pecera and Acuña.
y también verte la reflexión sobre los regresos de Pecera y de Acuña.
阿根廷南部，显然在之前的市场中这里移动了很多。
to the south of Argentina, which obviously moved a lot here in the previous market.
al sur argentino, que obviamente movieron mucho acá en el mercado anterior.
在给出清单之前我亲自谈过
I talked about it personally before giving the list
lo hablé personalmente antes de dar la lista
从逻辑上讲，他没有参加过训练，现在把他列入这份名单还为时过早。
Logically, he had not been training and it was very premature to put him on this list.
Lógicamente no venía entrenando y era muy prematuro correrlo en esta lista.
赫尔曼和马科斯的谈话和回归，首先
the conversation and the returns of Germán and Marcos, well, first
la conversación y los regresos de Germán y Marcos, bueno, primero
在权力不集中的时代
and in a time without concentrated powers
y en un tiempo sin competencias concentradas
进行任何修改，
to make any modification,
para hacer alguna modificación,
因为现在球队很好，我认为我们不必考虑......
because right now the team is fine and I don't think we have to think about...
porque ahora mismo el equipo está bien y no creo que haya que pensar en...
分析团队在哪些方面做得很好。
analyzing what the team is doing well.
analizando que lo que el equipo está bien.
这支球队的一大优点是每个人都知道他们在玩什么。
The great virtue that this team has is that everyone knows what they are playing.
La gran virtud que tiene este equipo es que todo el mundo sabe a lo que juega.
现在改变是件好事。
and that for now a change would be good.
y que por ahora un cambio sería bueno.
我认为最好的比赛是对阵法国队。
I think the best game was against France.
creo que en el mejor partido que fue contra Francia.
它被淘汰了。
It was eliminated.
Quedó eliminada.
下次见
and see you next time
y nos vemos la próxima
进入游戏的本质，他有一个非常好的段落，并且......
getting into the essence of the game, he had a very good passage and...
metiendo en esencia de juego, ha tenido un pasaje muy bueno y...
他们可以为我们做出贡献，所以我认为并不总是
that they can contribute to us, so I think that not always
que nos pueden aportar a nosotros, así que yo creo que no siempre
已经表明，即使在困难中，因为他已经
has shown that even in difficulty because he has had
ha demostrado que aún en dificultad porque ha tenido
奥运会虽然遭到了俱乐部的拒绝，但我仍然认为
Olympic with the rejections from the clubs and all that, I still think that
olímpico con los rechazos de los clubes y todo eso aún así creo que
你应得什么或者你对智利队有何看法？
What do you deserve or what do you think of the Chilean team?
¿Qué te merece o qué piensas del equipo chileno?
需要积分，很年轻，没有多少人物。
in need of points, very young, without many figures.
necesitado de puntos, muy joven, sin muchas figuras.
与黄金一代一样久负盛名，这次由里卡多·加里卡（Ricardo Garica）领导。
as renowned for as long as in the golden generation, and this time headed by Ricardo Garica.
tan renombrada por tanto tiempo como en la generación dorada, y esta vez encabezada por Ricardo Garica.
他的教练总是灌输踢好足球的理念。
His coach always instills playing football well.
Su entrenador siempre inculca jugar bien el fútbol.
嗯，据我所知，他正在经历一段……
and well, from what I see he is going through a moment of...
y bueno, por lo que veo está atravesando un momento de...
他一直有一句话很好
He has always had a very good word
siempre ha tenido palabra muy buena
以色列在宁静中的样子
with what Israel looks like in tranquility
con lo que se ve Israel en tranquilidad
3频道和体育中心，两个问题，第一如果在教练组内当然对你来说是一个很大的挑战
channel 3 and the sports center, two questions, the first if within the coaching staff of course it is a great challenge for you
la cadena 3 y la central deportiva, dos preguntas, la primera si dentro del cuerpo técnico por supuesto es un gran desafío para ustedes
事实上，至少在前两场比赛中，无论是没有梅西，还是有迪玛利亚，两人中的一个总是在一起。
The fact of living together, at least in these first two games, both without Messi and with Di María, one of the two was always there.
El hecho de convivir, al menos en estos dos primeros partidos, tanto sin Messi como con Di María, siempre alguno de los dos estaba.
另一位则说加雷卡，梅西不在就好了，智利缺少即将退役的布拉沃，桑切斯也受伤了。
and the other said Gareca that it was better that Messi was not there, Chile is missing Bravo who is retiring and Sánchez is injured.
y la otra dijo Gareca que era mejor que no esté Messi, a Chile le falta Bravo que se retira y Sánchez lesionado.
教练组并不反对。
The coaching staff is not opposed.
El cuerpo técnico no es que sea opuesto.
相反，当我们在国家队时，我们就听从男孩们的指挥。
On the contrary, when we are in the national team we are at the disposal of the boys.
Al contrario, cuando estamos en la selección estamos a disposición de los chicos.
从逻辑上讲，他们两个不是一个总是很奇怪。
and logically it is always strange that the two of them are not one.
y lógicamente siempre es extraño que no estén uno ellos dos.
我们需要一切...
and we need everything...
y necesitamos que todo...
比赛和伤亡情况
match and regarding casualties
partido y en cuanto a las bajas
不用我说，他们在国家队创造了历史，他们都是著名的球员。
I don't need to say it, they have made history in their national team and they have been renowned players.
No hace falta que lo diga yo, que han hecho historia en su selección y que han sido jugadores de renom.
打球真是令人难以置信，但是哦，好吧。
playing is incredible, but oh well.
jugar es increíble, pero bueno.
总是一样的事情，足球是如此奇怪，以至于最终你永远无法
The same thing always, football is so strange that in the end you can never
Lo mismo siempre, el fútbol es tan extraño que al final nunca te puede
来自Universo Deportivo 的莱昂内尔·埃尔南德斯。
Lionel Hernández from Universo Deportivo.
Lionel Hernández de Universo Deportivo.
到目前为止，您对这些首个排位赛日期以及总体排位赛进展有何分析？
What analysis do you make so far of these first qualifying dates, of the qualifying progress in general?
¿Qué análisis haces hasta ahora de estas primeras fechas de eliminatorias, de la marcha de eliminatorias en general?
以及目前厄瓜多尔需要的阿根廷教练数量 维卡塞兹、加盟巴拉圭的古斯塔沃·阿尔法罗
and the number of Argentine coaches that are now required Vicasez in Ecuador, Gustavo Alfaro who joins Paraguay
y de la cantidad de entrenadores argentinos que hay requeridos ahora Vicasez en Ecuador, Gustavo Alfaro que se suma a Paraguay
不知道是不是最多的时候，之前的预选赛也有不少。
I don't know if it's the time when there are the most, but the previous qualifying round there were also quite a few.
Yo no sé si es la época que más hay, pero la anterior eliminatoria también había bastantes.
它已经丢失了。
and it has been lost.
y se ha perdido.
对我们来说这非常好，我希望他们做得很好。
For us it is very good and I hope they do well.
Para nosotros es muy bueno y ojalá les vaya bien.
莱昂内尔怎么样？
How about Lionel?
¿Qué tal Lionel?
早上好，Unique 团队的 Mayra Varela。
Good morning, Mayra Varela for Unique Team.
Buenos días, Mayra Varela para Equipo Único.
我想问你两个问题。
I want to ask you two questions.
Te quiero hacer dos consultas.
首先，你刚才提到了九月约会的不舒服。
The first, you just said about the discomfort of the September date.
La primera, recién decías de la incomodidad de la fecha de septiembre.
球员们改变了俱乐部，超越了他们的个人和个人成长
The players have changed clubs, beyond their personal and individual growth
los jugadores han cambiado de club, más allá de su crecimiento personal y individual
由于教练的更换以及这些俱乐部的训练方式的变化，这也让人感到不舒服。
It is also uncomfortable because of the change of coaches and the change in training that those clubs have.
Es también incómodo por el cambio de entrenadores y el cambio de entrenamiento que tienen esos clubes.
关于阿根廷国家队，我想问你的另一件事是关于你所看到的阿根廷联赛
regarding the Argentine national team and the other thing I want to ask you is regarding the Argentine league as you are seeing it
en cuanto a la selección argentina y la otra que te quiero hacer es en cuanto a la liga argentina como la estás viendo
竞争激烈，球队通常不在积分榜上名列前茅。
competitive, with teams that are not usually at the top of the table.
competitiva, con equipos que habitualmente no están arriba de la tabla.
谢谢。
Gracias.
关于其他俱乐部的球员变动。
Regarding player changes to other clubs.
En cuanto a los cambios de jugadores a otros clubes.
改变我们的并不是那么多
it's not so much what changes us
no es tanto lo que nos cambia
他们已经去了其他俱乐部，但现在还不是时候，那么如果他们到达新俱乐部，他们就会开始了解
that they have gone to other clubs and it is not the time, then if they are arriving at their new clubs, they are getting to know
que se hayan ido a otros clubes y no es el momento, después si están llegando a sus nuevos clubes, están conociendo
对他的队友、教练来说，有些还没有上场。
to his teammates, coaches, some have not played yet.
a sus compañeros, entrenadores, algunos todavía no han jugado.
这可能会影响我们，但两三个月后就会成为问题。
That can affect us, but in two or three months that will be a problem.
Eso sí que nos puede afectar, pero dentro de dos o tres meses ya eso será un
不是故事，但现在是了，现在仍然不舒服。
not a story, but now it is, now it is still uncomfortable.
una historia que no, pero ahora sí, ahora sí que no deja de ser incómodo.
阿根廷锦标赛的竞争非常激烈。
The Argentine championship is very competitive.
El campeonato argentino es muy competitivo.
你现在所看到的正在经历一个伟大的时刻并且正在标志着
that what you see now is going through a great moment and is marking
que lo que veis ahora está atravesando un gran momento y está marcando
而其他队伍也在后面追赶。
and the other teams are chasing behind.
y los demás equipos van persiguiendo atrás.
好处是那里有很多团队。
and the good thing is that there are many teams there.
y lo bueno es que hay muchos equipos ahí.
就在那里，直到最后。
up there and it will be until the end.
ahí arriba y va a ser hasta el final.
希望人们喜欢它。
Let's hope people enjoy it.
Esperemos que la gente lo disfrute.
来自维塔利姆斯 (Vitalimus) 的埃诺城广播电台 (Radio Ciudad de Hainaut) 的莱昂内尔 (Lionel)、马克西 (Maxi)，我们正在直播。
Lionel, Maxi from Vitalimus for Radio Ciudad de Hainaut, we are live.
Lionel, Maxi de Vitalimus para Radio Ciudad de Henao, estamos en vivo.
但这也让你很容易说，我对未来有很多思考。
but it also makes it very easy for you to say well, I have plenty of material thinking about the future.
pero también te da mucha facilidad para decir bueno, tengo material de sobra pensando en el futuro.
你如何看待这种情况，你如何处理它。
how you see that situation, how you handle it.
cómo vas viendo esa situación, cómo la vas manejando.
考虑下一个排位赛日期，也考虑这个和下一个排位赛日期。
thinking about the next qualifying dates, thinking about this one and the next ones too.
pensando en las próximas fechas deliminatorias, pensando en esta y en las próximas también.
材料永远不够，材料越多，我们想要的就越好。
There is never enough material, the more there is, the better we want.
material de sobra nunca hay mejor que cuanto más haya mejor queremos
这是积极的，因为它提高了竞争力水平。
That is positive because it raises the level of competitiveness.
que eso es positivo porque alcha el nivel de competitividad.
好吧，正如我之前所说，我认为他们将根据我们创造的内容进入或发挥作用。
Well, and what I said before, I think they are going to enter or play based on what we create.
Bueno, y lo que dije antes creo que van a entrar o a jugar en base a lo que creamos.
对于国家队来说幸运的是，球队有他们的基地
Luckily for the national team the team has a base for them
por suerte para la selección el equipo tiene una base para ellos
他曾担任过的职位。
the positions in which he has done.
las posiciones en las que ha hizo.
合适的时机。
opportune moment.
momento oportuno.
但有时候训练、和教练一起看视频……
But sometimes training, watching a video with the coach...
Pero a veces el entrenar, el ver un video con el entrenador...
必须是
has to be
tiene que estar
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
再会。
Good day.
Buen día.
我们正在直播布宜诺斯艾利斯广播电台 AMM 350。
We are live for Radio Buenos Aires AMM 350.
Estamos en vivo para Radio Buenos Aires AMM 350.
周一，我们采访了卢卡斯·卡斯特罗曼。
On Monday we spoke with Lucas Castroman.
El lunes hablamos con Lucas Castroman.
谈到他，问他你正在领导的进程，他说这是世界足坛最好的。
And speaking about him, asking him precisely about the process you are leading, he said that it was the best in world football.
Y hablando de él, preguntándole justamente por el proceso que estás encabezando, él dijo que era el mejor del fútbol mundial.
分析一下，两届美洲杯，一次在意大利夺冠的决赛，多年后的世界杯。
Analyze this, two American Cups, a very final winning the move in Italy, a world cup after so many years.
Analíces esto, dos copas américa, una finalísima ganando la move en Italia, una copa del mundo después de tantos años.
你把它放在哪里或者哪里，你对德国杯正式开始的这个过程做了什么分析？
Where do you put it or where, what analysis do you make of this process that officially started that German Cup?
¿dónde ponen vos o adónde, qué análisis hacen de este proceso que arrancó oficialmente aquella copa alemana?
正如我的同事所说，2019 年美国的情况。
of America, as my colleague said, in 2019.
de América, como decía mi colega, en el 2019.
好吧，我不能告诉你，我不是一个会分析哪里的人......
Well, I couldn't tell you, I'm not one to analyze where...
Bueno, no sabría decirte, tampoco soy de analizar en dónde...
好吧。
and well.
y bueno.
没有人考虑过这个问题，或者至少很难考虑。
Nobody thought about it or at least it was difficult to think about.
ninguno lo pensaba o por lo menos era difícil de pensar.
所有这一切的重要一点是事情是可以做的。
The important thing about all this is that things can be done.
Lo importante de todo esto es que se pueden hacer las cosas.
它们是可以获得的，我认为这就是
They can be obtained and that I think is what
se pueden conseguir y eso creo que es lo que
尤其是在这个肯定会到来的时刻。
and especially at a time that will surely come.
y sobre todo en un momento que seguramente vendrá.
他已经准备好了，他已经准备好举起
He's ready for it, he's ready to lift
está preparado para eso, está preparado para levantar
既然我们已经成为过去。
And since we are in the past.
y puesto estamos en lo pasado.
统计数据，说话的人的历史。
statistics, the history of those who speak.
estadísticas, la historia de los que hablan.
并考虑这个团队能够继续给予我们所有人想要的快乐。
and be thinking about this team being able to continue giving the joy that is what we all want.
y esté pensando en que este equipo pueda seguir dando la alegría que es lo que todos queremos.
最后两个问题。
Last two questions.
Últimas dos preguntas.
下午好，步行到第三。
Good afternoon, walking to the third.
Buenas tardes, andando al tercero.
首先，询问瓦伦丁·卡尔博尼 (Valentín Carboni)，他是本次电话会议中最年轻的。
First, ask about Valentín Carboni, who is the youngest in this call.
Primero consultarte por Valentín Carboni, que es el más joven de esta convocatoria.
昨天听了 Franco Mastanduono 的演讲后，我突然想到了这个触发点
and precisely this trigger comes to me after having listened to Franco Mastanduono yesterday
y justamente este disparador me surge después de haber escuchado ayer a Franco Mastanduono
17岁说有点怀念以前的生活
17 years old saying that he misses his old life a little bit
con 17 años diciendo que extraña un poquito su vieja vida
不被人注意，做任何男孩都能做的事情
that of going unnoticed and doing things that any boy can do
esa de pasar desapercibido y hacer las cosas que puede hacer cualquier chico
那个年龄，同时如果你非常依赖运动心理学
of that age and at the same time if you rely a lot on sports psychology
de esa edad y paralelamente si te apoyas mucho en la psicología del deporte
在神经科学等领域或者如果你说话的话。
in the neuroscience of etcetera or if you talk.
en la neurociencia de etcétera o si hablás.
与男孩们进行大量的交流，使他们在面对呼吁时更加脚踏实地
a lot of voice with the boys so that they are more grounded in the face of the call for
mucho voz con los chicos para que por ahí estén más con los pies en la tierra ante la convocatoria de
正是他的国家的选择。
precisely the selection of his country.
justamente la selección de su país.
加上其他影响，你确实面临着困惑的风险。
with other repercussions, you do run the risk of getting confused.
con otras repercusiones, si que corres el riesgo de confundirte.
一切突然降临在他身上，然后……
Everything has fallen on him suddenly and...
le ha caído todo de repente y...
足球很糟糕，当他们年轻的时候，也许有人能让你相信这一点。
That football sucks and when they are young, maybe someone can make you believe it.
que jode el fútbol y cuando son jóvenes a lo mejor alguno te lo puede hacer creer
让你周围的每个人，你的同事，你的家人，你周围的人都能够理解它。
Let everyone around you, your colleagues, your family, the people around you make it understood.
que todo el entorno, sus compañeros, su familia, la gente que está alrededor se lo haga entender.
重要的是，他们不要失去本质并将自己与这一切隔离开来，但他们周围的人
It is important that they do not lose that essence and isolate themselves from all that, but the people around them are
es importante que no pierdan esa esencia y que se aíslen de todo eso, pero la gente que está alrededor es
他们不会这么做，他们唯一要做的就是周日他们上场时，尽力做到最好，玩得开心。
They are not going to do it, the only thing they are going to do is on Sunday when they go out on the field, try to do their best, have a good time.
no lo van a hacer, lo único que van a hacer es el domingo cuando salgan a la cancha intentar dar lo mejor, pasarla bien
从那里开始发生的事情取决于他们
and from there what happens depends on them
y a partir de ahí lo que pase lo depende de ellos
你对他加盟马德里竞技有何看法？
What do you think of his arrival at Atlético de Madrid?
¿Qué te parece su llegada al Atlético de Madrid?
连续性和所有权，并离开像曼城这样重要的球队。
continuity and ownership and leaving a team as important as Manchester City.
continuidad y titularidad y saliendo de un equipo tan importante como el Manchester City.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
他们笑了，然后……
They laugh and...
ríen y que...
如果对他来说一切顺利，那么拔牙也会顺利进行，但事实是，这个决定是个人的。
If it goes well for him, the extraction will go well, but the truth is that the decision has been personal.
si le va bien a él le va a ir bien a la extracción, pero la decisión la verdad que ha sido personal.